<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE appendix PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Configuration_Tool" remap="TID_8674">
	<title>Configuration Tool</title>
	<para>
		Installing the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager modifies only a subset of configuration settings from their defaults. Further modifications are made using the configuration tool: <command>rhevm-config</command>.
	</para>
	<para>
		The configuration tool does not require JBoss or the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager to be running to update the configuration. Configuration key values are stored in the database; configuration changes will not be saved unless the database is operational. Changes are applied when JBoss is restarted.
	</para>
	<para>
		The Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager stores configuration settings as a series of key-to-value pair mappings. The configuration tool allows you to:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				list all available configuration keys,
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				list all available configuration values,
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				retrieve the value of a specific configuration key, and
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				set the value of a specific configuration key.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		You are also able to maintain multiple versions of the manager's configuration with the configuration tool. Use the <parameter>--cver</parameter> parameter to specify the configuration version to be used when retrieving or setting a value for a configuration key. The default configuration version is <literal>general</literal>.
	</para>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=8674-160903+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=Red+Hat+Enterprise+Virtualization+Manager&amp;component=Guides-Install">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>