<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Configuring_the_Manager" remap="TID_7520">
	<title>Configuring oVirt Engine</title>
	<para>
		Once package installation is complete the oVirt Engine must be configured. The <command>engine-setup</command> command is provided to assist with this task. The script asks you a series of questions, the answers to which form the basis for system configuration. Once all required values have been provided the updated configuration is applied and the oVirt Engine services are started.
	</para>
	<procedure id="proc-Installation_Guide-Installing_the_RHEV_Manager-Configuration">
		<step>
			<title>Start setup script</title>
			<para>
				To begin configuring the system run <command>engine-setup</command> as the <systemitem class="username"> root</systemitem> user.
			</para>
			<screen># engine-setup</screen>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Override Apache configuration</title>
			<para>
				ovirt-engine uses the <systemitem>mod_proxy</systemitem> module for the Apache web server (<systemitem>httpd</systemitem>) to redirect network traffic from the <acronym>HTTP</acronym> and <acronym>HTTPS</acronym> ports which you select, to the application server that the Manager runs on. If the <command>engine-setup</command> script detects an existing <systemitem>httpd</systemitem> configuration then you will need to decide whether or not to override it:
			</para>
			<screen>Do you wish to override current httpd configuration and restart the service? ['yes'| 'no']  [yes] :</screen>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						If you do not receive this message, there is no existing <systemitem>httpd</systemitem> configuration on the system and the script will move to the next step.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						If you do receive this message, you must: 
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									enter <literal>yes</literal> if you wish to configure the Manager to listen to <acronym>HTTP</acronym> and/or <acronym>HTTPS</acronym> ports lower than port <literal>1024</literal>; or
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									enter <literal>no</literal> if you do not wish to configure the Manager to listen to <acronym>HTTP</acronym> and/or <acronym>HTTPS</acronym> ports lower than port <literal>1024</literal>, leaving the existing <systemitem>httpd</systemitem> configuration intact.
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Set Port for <acronym>HTTP</acronym></title>
			<para>
				The script prompts for entry of the port to use for <acronym>HTTP</acronym> communication. To use the default value, <literal>80</literal>, press <keycap> Enter</keycap>. To use an alternative value enter it in the field, and then press <keycap> Enter</keycap>.
			</para>
			<screen>HTTP Port  [80] :</screen>
			<para>
				The port you select also appears in the <acronym> URL</acronym> that must be used to access the oVirt Engine over <acronym> HTTP</acronym>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Set Port for <acronym>HTTPS</acronym></title>
			<para>
				The script prompts for entry of the port to use for <acronym> HTTPS</acronym> communication. To use the default value, <literal>443</literal>, press <keycap> Enter</keycap>. To use an alternative value enter it in the field, and then press <keycap> Enter</keycap>.
			</para>
			<screen>HTTPS Port  [443] :</screen>
			<para>
				Where a port other than <literal>443</literal> is selected it changes the <acronym> URL</acronym> that must be used to access the oVirt Engine over <acronym> HTTPS</acronym>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Set Fully Qualified Domain Name (<acronym>FQDN</acronym>)</title>
			<para>
				The script prompts for entry of the system's fully qualified domain name. This name should be resolvable via both forward and reverse <acronym> DNS</acronym> lookup. The script attempts to determine the fully qualified domain name automatically. The value identified is listed in square brackets as the default setting for the fully qualified domain name, based on your setup.
			</para>
			<screen>Host fully qualified domain name, note that this name should be fully resolvable  [manager.demo.redhat.com] :</screen>
			<para>
				Where the automatically determined fully qualified domain name is correct, press <keycap> Enter</keycap> to use the value and continue. Where the automatically determined fully qualified domain name is not correct, enter the correct value and press <keycap> Enter</keycap> to use the new value and continue.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Set Administrator Password</title>
			<para>
				The script creates an authentication domain internal to the oVirt Engine for the default administrative account. The domain is named <systemitem> internal</systemitem>, the administrative user is called <systemitem> admin</systemitem>. External authentication domains are added as a post-installation step using the <command>engine-manage-domains</command> command.
			</para>
			<para>
				You must choose a password for the <systemitem class="username"> admin</systemitem> user. You will be asked to enter it a second time to confirm your selection.
			</para>
			<screen>Password for Administrator (admin@internal) :</screen>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Set Organization Name</title>
			<para>
				The script prompts for entry of the Organization Name. The Organization Name appears in the <literal>Subject</literal> field of the certificate used to secure communications with the oVirt Engine.
			</para>
			<screen>Organization Name for the Certificate :</screen>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Configure Default Storage Type</title>
			<para>
				The script prompts for selection of the default storage type. This is the storage type that is used for the <literal>Default</literal> data center. You are able to add further data centers that use different storage types from the Administration Portal at any time.
			</para>
			<screen>The default storage type you will be using  ['NFS'| 'FC'| 'ISCSI']  [NFS] :</screen>
			<para>
				The default selection is Network File System (<literal>NFS</literal>). The other available values are: 
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Fibre Channel (<literal>FC</literal>), and
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Internet Small Computer System Interface (<literal>ISCSI</literal>).
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist> The <literal>NFS</literal>, <literal>FC</literal>, and <literal>ISCSI</literal> options are used to connect to remote storage. ovirt-engine also supports The <literal>LOCALFS</literal> storage type which allows the use of local storage attached to the virtualization hosts, but this storage type is not supported for the <literal>Default</literal> data center.
			</para>
			<para>
				To use the default selection, <literal>NFS</literal>, press <keycap> Enter</keycap>. To select <literal>FC</literal>, or <literal>ISCSI</literal> then enter the value and then press <keycap> Enter</keycap>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Select database location</title>
			<para>
				ovirt-engine supports the use of a local database on the management system, or a remote database provided elsewhere in your environment. The setup script prompts you to indicate whether you wish to use a local database, which is the default option, or a remote database:
			</para>
			<screen>Enter DB type for installation ['remote'| 'local']  [local] :</screen>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						Enter <literal>local</literal> to have the setup script create a local Postgresql database server for the Manager.
					</para>
					<para>
						The script prompts for entry of a password to use for the local oVirt Engine database. Enter the desired password. You will be asked to enter the password again to confirm it.
					</para>
					<screen>Database password (required for secure authentication with the locally created database) :</screen>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Enter <literal>remote</literal> to have the script use a remote database server for the Manager.
					</para>
					<substeps>
						<step>
							<para>
								You will be prompted to provide: 
								<itemizedlist>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											the <acronym>IP</acronym> address or hostname of the remote database server,
										</para>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											the port number on which the remote database server is listening,
										</para>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											the administrative user name for the remote database server, and
										</para>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											the administrative user's password.
										</para>
									</listitem>
								</itemizedlist> The administrative user provided must have the required permissions to create databases on the remote database server.
							</para>
							<screen>
Enter DB type for installation ['remote'| 'local']  [local] : remote      
Enter the host IP or host name where DB is running: database.demo.redhat.com
Enter DB port number  [5432] : 5432
Enter DB admin user name  [postgres] : 
Remote database password :
Confirm password :                
              				</screen>
						</step>
						<step>
							<title>Secure connection</title>
							<para>
								You can configure oVirt Engine to use a secure connection, encrypted using <acronym>SSL</acronym> when connecting to the remote database server.
							</para>
							<screen>Configure secure connection? ['yes'| 'no']  [no] :</screen>
							<para>
								Enter <literal>yes</literal> to use secure database connections.
							</para>
						</step>
					</substeps>
					<para>
						The setup script will connect to the remote database server to verify the details that you provided are correct.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Configure NFS ISO Domain</title>
			<para>
				The script asks whether or not an <acronym> NFS</acronym> share should be configured on the server and used as an <acronym> ISO</acronym> storage domain.
			</para>
			<screen>Should the installer configure NFS share on this server to be used as an ISO Domain? ['yes'| 'no']  [yes] :</screen>
			<para>
				An <acronym> ISO</acronym> storage domain is used to store copies of removable media for use when provisioning and using virtual machines. The oVirt Engine is able to use either an <acronym> ISO</acronym> storage domain on the system it is installed to or one that exists on remote storage. In either case the <acronym> ISO</acronym> storage domain must be accessible via <acronym> NFS</acronym>. The ability to configure an <acronym> ISO</acronym> storage domain is also available from the Administration Portal after installation.
			</para>
			<para>
				To take the default action, which is to configure an <acronym> NFS</acronym> share for use as an <acronym> ISO</acronym> storage domain, press <keycap> Enter</keycap>. To skip this step type <literal>no</literal> and press <keycap> Enter</keycap>.
			</para>
			<para>
				If you chose to configure an <acronym> NFS</acronym> share then you will also need to provide both a path and a display name for it. The path is the location on the local file system where the <acronym> NFS</acronym> share must be created. The directory must not already exist.
			</para>
			<screen>Mount point path:</screen>
			<para>
				The display name is the name the storage domain will appear under in the oVirt Engine. The display name must not contain non-alphanumeric characters other than the underscore (<literal>_</literal>) and the hyphen (<literal>-</literal>).
			</para>
			<screen>Display name for the ISO domain:</screen>
			<para>
				The <acronym> ISO</acronym> domain will be created and exported as an <acronym> NFS</acronym> share. It will be shown as active in the oVirt Engine once the first active virtualization host has been added to the <literal>Default</literal> data center.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Configure Firewall</title>
			<para>
				The oVirt Engine requires that network traffic on a number of ports be allowed through the system's firewall. The <command>engine-setup</command> script is able to configure this automatically, but selecting this option overrides any existing firewall configuration. Where there is an existing firewall configuration that needs to be maintained you must manually configure the firewall to include the additional rules required by the oVirt Engine.
			</para>
			<screen>
Firewall ports need to be opened.
You can let the installer configure iptables automatically overriding the current configuration. The old configuration will be backed up.
Alternately you can configure the firewall later using an example iptables file found under /usr/share/ovirt-engine/conf/iptables.example
Configure iptables ? ['yes'| 'no']:
</screen>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						To proceed with automatic firewall configuration type <literal>yes</literal> and then press <keycap> Enter</keycap>.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						To skip automatic firewall configuration type <literal>no</literal> and then press <keycap> Enter</keycap>. You will need to add rules equivalent to those found in <filename>/usr/share/ovirt-engine/conf/iptables.example</filename> to your <command>iptables</command> configuration.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Confirm Configuration</title>
			<para>
				You have now provided the script with all the information required to complete configuration of the oVirt Engine. The values which you entered are displayed for confirmation.
			</para>
			<example>
				<title>Configuration Confirmation Screen</title>
				<screen>
oVirt Engine will be installed using the following configuration:
=================================================================
http-port:                     80
https-port:                    443
host-fqdn:                     manager.demo.redhat.com
auth-pass:                     ********
org-name:                      Red Hat
default-dc-type:               NFS
db-remote-install:             local
db-local-pass:                 ********
nfs-mp:                        /isoshare
iso-domain-name:               ISODomain
config-nfs                     yes
override-iptables:             yes
Proceed with the configuration listed above? (yes|no): 
</screen>
			</example>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<para>
						To permanently apply the configuration values listed type <literal>yes</literal> and then press <keycap> Enter</keycap> to apply the configuration.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						If one or more of the configuration values listed is incorrect type <literal>no</literal> and then <keycap> Enter</keycap> to revisit the configuration.
					</para>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
			<para>
				The configuration values are applied. A number of services need to be started and as a result this step takes some time. Do not terminate the installation once application of the configuration values has commenced.
			</para>
			<para>
				Once the script has completed successfully take note of the additional information it provides. In particular note down the <literal>SSH Certificate fingerprint</literal>, <literal>SSH Public key fingerprint</literal>, and oVirt Engine <acronym> URL</acronym> for your records.
			</para>
			<example>
				<title>Successful Configuration</title>
				<screen>Installing:
Creating JBoss Profile...                                [ DONE ]
Creating CA...                                           [ DONE ]
Setting Database Security...                             [ DONE ]
Creating Database...                                     [ DONE ]
Updating the Default Data Center Storage Type...         [ DONE ]
Editing JBoss Configuration...                           [ DONE ]
Editing oVirt Engine Configuration...                    [ DONE ]
Configuring the Default ISO Domain...                    [ DONE ]
Configuring Firewall (iptables)...                       [ DONE ]
Starting JBoss Service...                                [ DONE ]

 **** Installation completed successfully ******

     (Please allow oVirt Engine a few moments to start up.....)


Additional information:
 * SSL Certificate fingerprint: 4C:A4:8F:93:62:50:C1:63:C8:09:70:77:07:90:FD:65:5B:3C:E8:DD
 * SSH Public key fingerprint: fa:71:38:88:58:67:ae:f0:b1:17:fe:91:31:6c:66:6e
 * A default ISO share has been created on this host.
   If IP based access restrictions are required, please edit /isoshare entry in /etc/exports
 * The firewall has been updated, the old iptables configuration file was saved to /usr/share/ovirt-engine/conf/iptables.backup.103654-09092011_866
 * The installation log file is available at: /var/log/ovirt-engine/engine-setup_2011_09_09_10_32_56.log
 * Please use the user "admin" and password specified in order to login into oVirt Engine
 * To configure additional users, first configure authentication domains using the 'engine-manage-domains' utility
 * To access oVirt Engine please go to the following URL: http://manager.demo.redhat.com:8080
</screen>
			</example>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The oVirt Engine has been installed and configured successfully. You are now able to connect to the Administration Portal for the first time.
	</para>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=7520-163936+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=ovirt-engine&amp;component=doc-Installation_Guide">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>