<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Designating_a_Display_Network" remap="TID_7627">
	<title>Designating a Logical Network for a Specific Traffic Type in oVirt Engine</title>
	<para>
		A Logical Network created to carry specific network traffic must be designated as such using the Administration Portal. To designate a Logical Netwok for specific network traffic:
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select the <guilabel>Clusters</guilabel> tab, and select the Cluster the Logical Network is attached to.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select the <guilabel>Logical Networks</guilabel> sub-tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Assign/UnAssign Networks</guilabel> button.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Assign/UnAssign Networks</guilabel> dialog appears. Each Logical Network associated with the Cluster is listed. Additionally alongside each Logical Network these options are shown:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>Assign</guilabel> &mdash; When selected, the Logical Network is assigned to the Cluster. De-selecting the option unassigns the Logical Network from the Cluster. Do not unassign the Logical Network if their are active hosts within the Cluster. Ensure that the <guilabel>Assign</guilabel> option is selected for the Logical Network that you want to assign network trafic to.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>Required</guilabel> &mdash; When selected, the Logical Network is considered mandatory for Cluster operation. Hosts that are not attached to the Logical Network, and therefore not candidates for migration of Virtual Machines from hosts that are attached to the Logical Network, will be marked non-operational. This was the default behaviour for all Logical Networks assigned to a Cluster in previous versions of oVirt.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>VM Network</guilabel> &mdash; When selected, the Logical Network is used for all Virtual Machine network traffic, excluding console connections.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>Display Network</guilabel> &mdash; When selected the Logical Network is used for all network traffic generated by console connections to Virtual Machines.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>
				Select the desired options for each Logical Network shown, then click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		You have successfully designated a Logical Network for a specific network traffic type.
	</para>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=7627-160903+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=oVirt&amp;component=doc-Installation_Guide">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>