<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Hypervisor_Interactive_Installation" remap="TID_7610">
	<title>Installing the Node Interactively</title>
	<para>
		oVirt Nodes are able to use Storage Area Networks (<acronym>SANs</acronym>) and other network storage for storing virtualized guest images. Nodes can be installed on <acronym> SANs</acronym>, provided that the Host Bus Adapter (<acronym>HBA</acronym>) permits configuration as a boot device in <acronym> BIOS</acronym>.
	</para>
	<para>
		Hypervisors are able to use multipath devices for installation. Multipath is often used for <acronym>SANs</acronym> or other networked storage. Multipath is enabled by default at install time. Any block device which responds to <command>scsi_id</command> functions with multipath. Devices where this is not the case include <acronym> USB</acronym> storage and some older <acronym> ATA</acronym> disks.
	</para>
	<para>
		There are two methods for installing oVirt Nodes:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Interactive Installation, documented here; and 
				<!-- (see <xref linkend="sect-Deployment_Guide-Installing_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization_Hypervisors-Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization_Hypervisor_interactive_installation" />)-->.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Unattended installation.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		For information about unattended installation, refer to the <citetitle>Fedora — Node Deployment Guide</citetitle>.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<step>
			<para>
				To commence Node installation select <guilabel>Install Node</guilabel> and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Keyboard Selection</title>
			<para>
				The Keyboard screen allows you to configure the appropriate keyboard layout for your locale. Use the arrow keys to highlight the appropriate option. To save your selection, use <keycap>Tab</keycap> to move to <guilabel>Apply</guilabel>, and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
			</para>
			<example>
				<title>Keyboard Layout Configuration</title>
				<screen><![CDATA[Keyboard Layout Selection

| Swiss German (latin1)                |
| Slovak (qwerty)                      |
| Slovenian                            |
| Serbian                              |
| Serbian (latin)                      |
| Swedish                              |
| Turkish                              |
| Ukrainian                            |
| United Kingdom                       |
| *** U.S. English ******************* |

<Apply>   <Reset>]]></screen>
			</example>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Disk Configuration</title>
			<para>
				The installation script automatically detects all disks attached to the system. This information is used to assist with selection of the boot and installation disks that the Node should use. Each entry displayed on these screens indicates the <guilabel>Location</guilabel>, <guilabel>Device Name</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Size (GB)</guilabel> of the relevant disk.
			</para>
			<substeps>
				<step>
					<title>Boot disk</title>
					<para>
						The first disk selection screen is used to select the disk from which the Node will boot. the Node's boot loader will be installed to the Master Boot Record ( <acronym> MBR</acronym>) of the disk that is selected on this screen. the Node attempts to automatically detect the disks attached to the system and presents the list from which you choose the boot device. Alternatively you are able to manually select a device, by specifying a block device name, by enabling the <guilabel>Other Device</guilabel> option.
					</para>
					<important>
						<title>Important — Boot Order</title>
						<para>
							The disk selected must be identified as a boot device and appear in the boot order either in the system's BIOS or in a pre-existing boot loader.
						</para>
					</important>
					<stepalternatives>
						<step>
							<title>Automatically Detected Device Selection</title>
							<substeps>
								<step>
									<para>
										Select the entry for the disk the Node is to boot from in the list.
									</para>
								</step>
								<step>
									<para>
										Select the <guibutton>&lt;Continue&gt;</guibutton> button and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>. This action will save the boot device selection and start the next step of installation.
									</para>
								</step>
							</substeps>
						</step>
						<step>
							<title>Manual Device Selection</title>
							<substeps>
								<step>
									<para>
										Select the <guilabel>Other Device</guilabel> entry from the list.
									</para>
								</step>
								<step>
									<para>
										Select the <guibutton>&lt;Continue&gt;</guibutton> button and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
									</para>
								</step>
								<step>
									<para>
										When prompted to <guilabel>Please enter the disk to use for booting RHEV Node</guilabel> enter the name of the block device from which the Node should boot.
									</para>
									<example>
										<title>Other Device Selection</title>
										<screen>Please enter the disk to use for booting RHEV Node
/dev/sda 
</screen>
									</example>
								</step>
								<step>
									<para>
										Select the <guibutton>&lt;Continue&gt;</guibutton> button and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>. This action will save the boot device selection and start the next step of installation.
									</para>
								</step>
							</substeps>
						</step>
					</stepalternatives>
					<para>
						Once a disk has been selected it is necessary to select the <guibutton>&lt;Continue&gt;</guibutton> button and press <keycap>Enter</keycap> to save the selection and continue with Node installation.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<title>Installation Disk(s)</title>
					<para>
						The disk(s) selected for installation will be those to which the Node itself is installed. the Node attempts to automatically detect the disks attached to the system and presents the list from which installation devices are chosen.
					</para>
					<warning>
						<title>Warning — Data Loss</title>
						<para>
							All data on the selected storage device(s) will be destroyed.
						</para>
					</warning>
					<substeps>
						<step>
							<para>
								Select each disk which the Node is to use for installation and press <keycap> Space</keycap> to toggle it to enabled. Repeat this step for all disks you want the Node to use. Where other devices are to be used for installation, either solely or in addition to those which are listed automatically, enable the <guilabel>Other Device</guilabel> option.
							</para>
						</step>
						<step>
							<para>
								Select the <guibutton>&lt;Continue&gt;</guibutton> button and press <keycap>Enter</keycap> to continue.
							</para>
						</step>
						<step>
							<para>
								Where the <guilabel>Other Device</guilabel> option was specified a further prompt will appear. Enter the name of each additional block device to use for Node installation separated by a comma. Once all required disks have been selected then select the <guibutton>&lt;Continue&gt;</guibutton> button and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
							</para>
							<example>
								<title>Other Device Selection</title>
								<screen>Please select the disk(s) to use for installation of RHEV Node
Enter multiple entries separated by commas
/dev/mmcblk0,/dev/mmcblk1______________
</screen>
							</example>
						</step>
					</substeps>
					<para>
						Once the installation disk, or disks, have been selected the next stage of the installation starts.
					</para>
				</step>
			</substeps>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Password</title>
			<para>
				the Node requires that a password be set to protect local console access by the <systemitem class="username"> admin</systemitem> user. The installation script prompts you to enter the desired password in both the <guilabel>Password</guilabel> and <guilabel>Confirm Password</guilabel> fields.
			</para>
			<para>
				A strong password must be used. Strong passwords consist of a mix of uppercase, lowercase, numeric, and punctuation characters. They are six or more characters long and do not contain dictionary words.
			</para>
			<para>
				Once a strong password has been entered select <guibutton>&lt;Install&gt;</guibutton> and press <keycap>Enter</keycap> to install the Node to disk.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		Once installation is complete the message <literal>RHEV Node Installation Finished Successfully</literal> will be displayed. Select the <guibutton>&lt;Restart&gt;</guibutton> button and press <keycap>Enter</keycap> to reboot the system.
	</para>
	<note>
		<title>Note — Remove Boot Media</title>
		<para>
			The boot media should be removed and the boot device order changed to prevent the installation sequence restarting after the system reboots.
		</para>
	</note>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=7610-160903+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=oVirt&amp;component=doc-Installation_Guide">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>