<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Installing_the_Hypervisor_Packages" remap="TID_7525">
	<title>Installing the oVirt Node Packages</title>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Summary</title>
		<para>
			The <systemitem>oVirt Node (v.6 x86_64)</systemitem> Red Hat Network channel contains the Node packages. the Node itself is contained in the <package>rhev-hypervisor6</package> package. Additional tools supporting <acronym>USB</acronym> and <acronym>PXE</acronym> installations are contained in the <package>rhev-hypervisor-tools</package> package. You must install the Node packages on the system that you intend to use to create Node boot media.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<procedure>
		<title>Installing the oVirt Node Packages</title>
		<step>
			<stepalternatives>
				<step>
					<title>Subscribing to download the Node using certificate-based RHN</title>
					<substeps>
						<step>
							<title>Identify Available Entitlement Pools</title>
							<para>
								To subscribe the system to the oVirt you must locare the identifier for the relevant entitlement pool. Use the <parameter>list</parameter> action of the <command>subscription-manager</command> to find these:
							</para>
							<para>
								To identify available subscription pools for <literal>oVirt</literal> use the command:
							</para>
							<screen># subscription-manager list --available | grep -A8 "oVirt"</screen>
							<note>
								<para>
									Beta releases of oVirt Node are distributed using an alternative channel. Beta releases consist of pre-release software. They must not be used in a production environment. The entitlement required to obtain beta releases of the oVirt Node is called <literal>oVirt Beta</literal>.
								</para>
							</note>
						</step>
						<step>
							<title>Subscribe System to Entitlement Pools</title>
							<para>
								Using the pool identifiers located in the previous step, subscribe the system to <literal>Fedora Server</literal>, <literal>oVirt</literal> entitlements. Use the <parameter>subscribe</parameter> parameter to the <command>subscription-manager</command> command, replacing <replaceable>POOLID</replaceable> with one of the pool identifiers.:
							</para>
							<screen># subscription-manager subscribe --pool=<replaceable>POOLID</replaceable></screen>
						</step>
					</substeps>
				</step>
				<step>
					<title>Subscribing to download the Node using RHN Classic</title>
					<substeps>
						<step>
							<para>
								Log on to Red Hat Network (<ulink url="http://rhn.redhat.com"/>).
							</para>
						</step>
						<step>
							<para>
								Move the mouse cursor over the <guilabel>Subscriptions</guilabel> link at the top of the page, and then click <guilabel>Registered Systems</guilabel> in the menu that appears.
							</para>
						</step>
						<step>
							<para>
								Select the system to which you are adding channels from the list presented on the screen, by clicking the name of the system.
							</para>
						</step>
						<step>
							<para>
								Click <guilabel>Alter Channel Subscriptions</guilabel> in the <guilabel>Subscribed Channels</guilabel> section of the screen.
							</para>
						</step>
						<step>
							<para>
								Select the <systemitem>oVirt Node (v.6 x86_64)</systemitem> channel from the list presented on the screen, then click the <guilabel>Change Subscription</guilabel> button to finalize the change.
							</para>
						</step>
					</substeps>
					<note>
						<para>
							Beta releases of oVirt Node are distributed using an alternative channel. Beta releases consist of pre-release software. They must not be used in a production environment. The entitlement required to obtain beta releases of the oVirt Node is called <systemitem>oVirt Node Beta (v.6 x86_64)</systemitem>.
						</para>
					</note>
				</step>
			</stepalternatives>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Log in to the system on which the oVirt Engine is installed. You must log in as the <systemitem>root</systemitem> user.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Use <command>yum</command> to install the <package>rhev-hypervisor6</package> and <package>rhev-hypervisor-tools</package> packages.
			</para>
			<screen># yum install rhev-hypervisor6 rhev-hypervisor-tools</screen>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result</title>
		<para>
			the Node ISO image is installed into the <filename>/usr/share/rhev-hypervisor/</filename> directory. The <command>rhevh-iso-to-disk</command> and <command>rhevh-iso-to-pxeboot</command> scripts are installed to the <filename>/usr/bin</filename> directory.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<note>
		<para>
			Fedora 6.2 and later allows more than one version of the ISO image to be installed at one time. As such, <filename>/usr/share/rhev-hypervisor/rhev-hypervisor.iso</filename> is now a symbolic link to a uniquely-named version of the Node ISO image, such as <filename>/usr/share/rhev-hypervisor/rhevh-6.2-20111006.0.el6.iso</filename>. Different versions of the image can now be installed alongside each other, allowing administrators to run and maintain a cluster on a previous version of the Node while upgrading another cluster for testing.
		</para>
		<para>
			Additionally, the symbolic links <filename>/usr/share/rhev-hypervisor/rhevh-latest6.iso</filename>, and <filename>/usr/share/rhev-hypervisor/rhev-hypervisor6.iso</filename> are created. These links also target the most recently installed version of the oVirt ISO image.
		</para>
	</note>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=7525-164513+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=oVirt&amp;component=doc-Installation_Guide">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>