<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Storage_Setup" remap="TID_8671">
	<title>Introduction to storage in ovirt-engine</title>
	<!--    <mediaobject>        <imageobject>            <imagedata fileref="images/813.png" />        </imageobject>    </mediaobject>-->
	<para>
		ovirt-engine uses a centralized storage system for virtual machine disk images, ISO files and snapshots. Storage networking can be implemented using Network File System (<acronym>NFS</acronym>), Internet Small Computer System Interface (<acronym>iSCSI</acronym>), Fibre Channel Protocol (<acronym>FCP</acronym>), local storage attached directly to the virtualization hosts, or other <acronym>POSIX</acronym> compliant filesystems. This section describes how to set up and manage the variety of storage types that can be used in the oVirt platform. Setting up storage is a vital prerequisite for a new data center because a data center cannot be initialized unless storage domains are attached and activated.
	</para>
	<para>
		A ovirt-engine system administrator needs to create, configure, attach and maintain storage for the virtualized enterprise. A familiarity with the storage types and their use is highly recommended. This document does not describe the concepts, protocols, requirements or general usage of <acronym>NFS</acronym>, <acronym>iSCSI</acronym>, <acronym>FCP</acronym>, local storage, or <acronym>POSIX</acronym> compliant filesystems. It is recommended that you read your storage array vendor's guides, and refer to the <citetitle>Fedora — Storage Administration Guide</citetitle> for more information on managing storage, if necessary.
	</para>
	<para>
		The ovirt-engine platform enables administrators to assign and manage storage effectively and efficiently. The <guilabel>Storage</guilabel> tab on the oVirt platform provides an efficient graphical way to view and manage networked storage. The <guilabel>Storage Results</guilabel> list displays all the storage domains, and the Details pane enables access to general information about the domain.
	</para>
	<para>
		ovirt-engine platform has three types of storage domains:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Data domains hold the disk images of all the virtual machines running in the system, operating system images and data disks. In addition, snapshots of the virtual machines are also stored in the data domain. The data cannot be shared across data centers, and the data domain must be of the same type as the data center. For example, a data center of a <acronym>iSCSI</acronym> type, must have an <acronym>iSCSI</acronym> data domain. A data domain cannot be shared between data centers.
			</para>
			<para>
				Additionally you must attach a data domain to a data center before you will be allowed to attach domains of other types to it.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<acronym>ISO</acronym> domains store <acronym>ISO</acronym> files (or logical <acronym>CDs</acronym>) used to install and boot operating systems and applications for the virtual machines. Because an <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain is a logical entity replacing a library of physical <acronym>CDs</acronym> or <acronym>DVDs</acronym>, an <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain removes the data center's need for physical media. An <acronym>ISO</acronym> domain can be shared across different data centers. <acronym>ISO</acronym> storage domains must be located on <acronym>NFS</acronym> storage.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				An export domain is a temporary storage repository that is used to copy/move images between data centers and oVirt Engine installations. In addition, the export domain can be used to backup virtual machines. An export domain can be moved between data centers, however, it can only be active in one data center at a time. Support for export storage domains backed by mechanisms other than <acronym>NFS</acronym> is being deprecated. New export storage domains must be created on <acronym>NFS</acronym> storage.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		Only commence configuring and attaching storage for your ovirt-engine environment once you have determined the storage needs of your data center(s).
	</para>
	<important>
		<title>Important — Before Adding Storage</title>
		<para>
			Before adding storage ensure that you have a working oVirt Engine environment. You must be able to successfully access the Administration Portal, and there must be at least one host connected with a status of <literal>Up</literal>.
		</para>
	</important>
	<important>
		<title>Important — Export Domain Storage Type</title>
		<para>
			Support for export storage domains backed by storage on anything other than <acronym>NFS</acronym> is being deprecated. While existing export storage domains imported from ovirt-engine 2.2 environments remain supported new export storage domains must be created on <acronym>NFS</acronym> storage.
		</para>
	</important>
	<formalpara role="link-list">
		<title/>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<xref linkend="Adding_FCP_Storage" xrefstyle="link-list"/>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<xref linkend="Adding_Local_Storage" xrefstyle="link-list"/>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<xref linkend="sect-Adding_NFS_Storage" xrefstyle="link-list"/>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<xref linkend="sect-Adding_iSCSI_Storage" xrefstyle="link-list"/>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=8671-163871+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=ovirt-engine&amp;component=doc-Installation_Guide">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>