<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Subscribing_to_Required_Channels_using_Subscription_Manager" remap="TID_10233">
	<title>Subscribing to Required Channels using Subscription Manager</title>
	<itemizedlist>
		<title role="process-previous-title">Previous Step in <link linkend="proc-Preparing_a_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_Host">Preparing a Red Hat Enterprise Linux Host</link></title>
		<listitem>
			<para role="process-previous-link">
				<xref linkend="Installing_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux"/>
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Summary</title>
		<para>
			To be used as a virtualization host a Red Hat Enterprise Linux host be registered and subscribed to a number of entitlements using either Subscription Manager or <acronym>RHN</acronym> Classic. You must follow the steps in this procedure if you wish to register and subscribe using Subscription Manager. Completion of this procedure will mean that you have: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						registered the virtualization host to Red Hat Network using Subscription Manager;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						subscribed the virtualization host to the <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server</literal> entitlement; and
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						subscribed the virtualization host to the <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</literal> entitlement.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist> Do <emphasis>not</emphasis> follow the steps in this procedure if you wish to register and subscribe using <acronym>RHN</acronym> Classic.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<procedure>
		<title>Subscribing to Required Channels using Subscription Manager</title>
		<step>
			<title>Register</title>
			<para>
				Run the <command>subscription-manager</command> command with the <parameter>register</parameter> parameter as the <systemitem>root</systemitem> user to register the system with the Red Hat Network. To complete registration successfully you will need to supply your Red Hat Network <guilabel>Username</guilabel> and <guilabel>Password</guilabel> when prompted.
			</para>
			<screen># subscription-manager register</screen>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Identify entitlement pools</title>
			<para>
				To subscribe the system to the correct entitlements you must first locate the identifiers for the required entitlement pools. Use the <parameter>list</parameter> action of the <command>subscription-manager</command> to find these.
			</para>
			<para>
				To identify available subscription pools for <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server</literal> use the command:
			</para>
			<screen># subscription-manager list --available | grep -A8 "Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server"</screen>
			<para>
				To identify available subscription pools for <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</literal> use the command:
			</para>
			<screen># subscription-manager list --available | grep -A8 "Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization"</screen>
			<note>
				<para>
					Beta releases of Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization are distributed using an alternative channel. Beta releases consist of pre-release software. They must not be used in a production environment. The entitlement required to obtain beta releases of the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization is called <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Beta</literal>.
				</para>
			</note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Subscribe to entitlements</title>
			<para>
				Using the pool identifiers that you located in the previous step, subscribe the system to <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server</literal>, and <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</literal> entitlements. Use the subscribe <parameter>parameter</parameter> to the <command>subscription-manager</command> command, replacing <parameter>POOLID</parameter> with one of the pool identifiers each time the command is run:
			</para>
			<screen># subscription-manager subscribe --pool=<parameter>POOLID</parameter></screen>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result</title>
		<para>
			You have registered the virtualization host to Red Hat Network and subscribed to the required entitlements using Subscription Manager.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<itemizedlist>
		<title role="process-next-title">Next Step in <link linkend="proc-Preparing_a_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_Host">Preparing a Red Hat Enterprise Linux Host</link></title>
		<listitem>
			<para role="process-next-link">
				<xref linkend="Subscribing_to_Required_Channels_using_RHN_Classic"/>
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=10233-163391+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=Red+Hat+Enterprise+Virtualization+Manager&amp;component=Guides-Install">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>