<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="Subscribing_to_the_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization_Manager_Channels_using_Subscription_Manager" remap="TID_10008">
	<title>Subscribing to the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager Channels using Subscription Manager</title>
	<procedure>
		<step>
			<para>
				Run the <command>subscription-manager <parameter>register</parameter></command> command to register the system with the Red Hat Network. To complete registration successfully you will need to supply your Red Hat Network <guilabel>Username</guilabel> and <guilabel>Password</guilabel> when prompted.
			</para>
			<screen># subscription-manager register</screen>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Identify Available Entitlement Pools</title>
			<para>
				To subscribe the system to Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization you must locate the identifiers for the relevant entitlement pools. Use the <parameter>list</parameter> action of the <command>subscription-manager</command> to find these.
			</para>
			<para>
				To identify available subscription pools for <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server</literal> use the command:
			</para>
			<screen>
# subscription-manager list --available | grep -A8 "Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server"        
      		</screen>
			<para>
				To identify available subscription pools for <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</literal> use the command:
			</para>
			<screen>
# subscription-manager list --available | grep -A8 "Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization"        
      		</screen>
			<para>
				To identify available subscription pools for <literal>JBoss Enterprise Application Platform</literal> use the command:
			</para>
			<screen>
# subscription-manager list --available | grep -A8 "JBoss Enterprise Application Platform"        
      		</screen>
			<note>
				<para>
					Beta releases of Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager are distributed using an alternative channel. Beta releases consist of pre-release software. They must not be used in a production environment. The entitlement required to obtain beta releases of Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager is called <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Beta</literal>.
				</para>
			</note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Subscribe System to Entitlement Pools</title>
			<para>
				Using the pool identifiers located in the previous step, subscribe the system to <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Linux Server</literal>, <literal>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</literal>, and <literal>JBoss Application Platform</literal> entitlements. Use the <parameter>subscribe</parameter> parameter to the <command>subscription-manager</command> command, replacing <replaceable>POOLID</replaceable> with one of the pool identifiers each time the command is run.:
			</para>
			<screen># subscription-manager subscribe --pool=<replaceable>POOLID</replaceable></screen>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The system is now registered with Red Hat Network and subscribed to the channels required for Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager installation.
	</para>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=10008-162838+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=Red+Hat+Enterprise+Virtualization+Manager&amp;component=Guides-Install">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>