<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="System_Components" remap="TID_8652">
	<title>System Components</title>
	<para>
		ovirt-engine platform consists of one or more virtualization hosts (either oVirt Nodes or Fedora 6.2, or higher, systems) and at least one manager. The virtual machines run on the virtualization hosts. The system and all its components are managed through a centralized management system.
	</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>oVirt Engine</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The oVirt Engine acts as a centralized management system that allows system administrators to view and manage virtual machines. The oVirt Engine provides a comprehensive range of features including search capabilities, resource management, live migrations and provisioning. The oVirt Engine itself also runs on Fedora&nbsp;17.
				</para>
				<para>
					The manager provides a graphical user interface to administer the physical and logical resources within the virtual environment infrastructure. It can be used to manage provisioning, connection protocols, user sessions, virtual machine pools, images and high availability/clustering. The oVirt Engine exposes an Administration Portal, a User Portal, and an Application Programming Interface (<acronym>API</acronym>).
				</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The Administration Portal is used to perform setup, configuration, and management of the ovirt-engine environment.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The User Portal is used to start, stop, reboot, and connect to virtual machines. Users granted power user access are also able to create virtual machine templates and, virtual machines from this interface.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <acronym>REST</acronym>&nbsp;<acronym>API</acronym> provides an interface for automation of tasks normally accomplished manually by users. Scripts that make use of the <acronym>REST</acronym><acronym>API</acronym> are able to be written in any language which supports accessing <acronym>HTTP</acronym> and <acronym>HTTPS</acronym> resources.
						</para>
						<para>
							Python bindings for the <acronym>REST</acronym>&nbsp;<acronym>API</acronym> are also provided, as well as an interface for interacting with the <acronym>API</acronym> from the command line.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>oVirt Node(s)</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The oVirt Node is a fully featured virtualization platform for quick, easy deployment and management of virtualized guests. the Node is designed for management via the oVirt Engine. It provides a thin virtualization layer deployed across the server infrastructure.
				</para>
				<para>
					Kernel-based Virtual Machine ( <acronym>KVM</acronym>), which is a core component of the Linux kernel, is used to provide virtualization. oVirt Node 6.3 and later are supported by this release of oVirt.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Fedora Host(s)</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The oVirt Engine also supports the use of systems running Fedora 6.3, or higher, <acronym>AMD64</acronym>/Intel 64 versions as virtualization hosts.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
	<simplesect>
		<title/>
		<para role="RoleCreateBugPara">
			<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/enter_bug.cgi?cf_environment=Instance+Name%3A+Not+Defined%0ABuild%3A+CSProcessor+Builder+Version+1.5%0ABuild+Filter%3A+null%0ABuild+Name%3A+%0ABuild+Date%3A+20-07-2012+14%3A00%3A28&amp;cf_build_id=8652-163891+20+Jul+2012+14%3A00+en-US&amp;product=ovirt-engine&amp;component=doc-Installation_Guide">Report a bug</ulink>
		</para>
	</simplesect>
</section>