<?xml version="1.0"?>
<section id="References_oVirt_3_Active_Directory">
   <title>Active Directory</title>
	<para>
		This section is intended to provide a brief overview of the <application>Active Directory</application> configuration required to support the directory services requirements of oVirt. It is not to be considered as a complete guide to the use of <application>Active Directory</application>. For full configuration procedures, refer to the appropriate Microsoft documentation available at <ulink url="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dd578336(WS.10).aspx"/>.
	</para>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Installation</title>
		<para>
			<application>Active Directory Domain Services</application>  must be installed and available prior to commencement of the oVirt Engine installation. For <application>Active Directory Domain Services</application> installation instructions, including the creation of a new <systemitem>Forest</systemitem> and associated <systemitem>Domain</systemitem>, refer to the Microsoft documentation at: <ulink url="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-au/library/cc772464(WS.10).aspx"/>.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Users</title>
		<para>
			The oVirt administrative user must be created prior to installation. The credentials of this user are required to complete oVirt Engine installation. It is the account used when logging into the oVirt Administration Portal to manage the system.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<para>
		The oVirt administrative user must have delegated control over the <systemitem>Domain</systemitem> to:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<systemitem>Join a computer to the domain</systemitem>.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				<systemitem>Modify the membership of a group</systemitem>.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		For information on creation of user accounts refer to <ulink url="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc732336.aspx"/>. 
	</para>
	<para>
		For information on delegation of control refer to <ulink url="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc732524.aspx"/>.
	</para>
	<important>
		<title>Important — Do <emphasis>not</emphasis> use the <systemitem class="username">Administrator</systemitem> user</title>
		<para>
			An Active Directory user account must be created specifically for use as the oVirt administrative user. Do <emphasis>not</emphasis> use the Active Directory <systemitem class="username">Administrator</systemitem> account as the oVirt Engine administrative user.
		</para>
	</important>
	
   <!-- Do not edit below this line! -->

   <!-- Injection Point: Related Overviews -->
   <!-- Injection Point: Related Concepts -->
   <!-- Injection Point: Related Tasks -->
</section>