<?xml version="1.0"?>
<section id="References_oVirt_3_Configuration_Tool">
   <title>Configuration Tool</title>
	<para>
		During installation, only a subset of oVirt Engine's configuration settings are modified from their defaults. You make further changes with the included configuration tool, <command>ovirt-config</command>. 
	</para>
	<para>
		The configuration tool does not require <acronym>JBoss</acronym> or oVirt Engine to be running to update the configuration. Configuration key values are stored in the database and as such it must be operational for configuration changes to be saved. Changes are only applied once <acronym>JBoss</acronym> is restarted.
	</para>
	<para>
		The engine's configuration is stored as a series of key to value pair mappings. The configuration tool allows you to:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				list all available configuration keys,
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				 list all available configuration values,
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				get the value of a specific configuration key, and
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				set the value of a specific configuration key.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		The configuration tool also allows you to maintain multiple versions of the engine's configuration. When getting or setting the value for a configuration key the <parameter>--cver</parameter> parameter is used to specify which configuration version is to be used. The default configuration version is <literal>general</literal>.
	</para>
	<section>
		<title>Syntax</title>
			<para>
				You will find the configuration tool on the machine to which oVirt Engine was installed. Common usage examples are discussed within this guide. For full usage information consult the <command>ovirt-config</command> command's help output:
			</para>
			<screen># <command>ovirt-config <parameter>--help</parameter></command></screen>
			<para/>
			<variablelist>
				<title>Common Tasks</title>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>List Available Configuration Keys</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Use the <parameter>--list</parameter> parameter to list available configuration keys.
						</para>
						<screen># <command>ovirt-config <parameter>--list</parameter></command></screen>
						<para>
							The tool lists each available configuration key by name. It also returns a description of each key's purpose.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>List Available Configuration Values</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Use the <parameter>--all</parameter> parameter to list available configuration values.
						</para>
						<screen># <command>ovirt-config <parameter>--all</parameter></command></screen>
						<para>
							The tool lists each available configuration key by name as well as the current value of the key, and the configuration version.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>	
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Get Value of Configuration Key</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Use the <parameter>--get</parameter> parameter to get the value of a specific key. 
						</para>
						<screen># <command>ovirt-config <parameter>--get <replaceable>KEY_NAME</replaceable></parameter></command></screen>
						<para>
							Replace <replaceable>KEY_NAME</replaceable> with the name of the key to retrieve. The tool returns the key name, value, and the configuration version. Optionally the <parameter>--cver</parameter> parameter is used to specify the configuration version from which the value should be retrieved.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Set Value of Configuration Key</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Use the <parameter>--set</parameter> parameter to set the value of a specific key. You must also set the configuration version to which the change is to apply using the <parameter>--cver</parameter> parameter.
						</para>
						<screen># <command>ovirt-config <parameter>--set <replaceable>KEY_NAME</replaceable>=<replaceable>KEY_VALUE</replaceable></parameter> <parameter>--cver=<replaceable>VERSION</replaceable></parameter></command></screen>
						<para>
							Replace <replaceable>KEY_NAME</replaceable> with the name of the key to set, and replace <replaceable>KEY_VALUE</replaceable> with the value to assign to it. In an environment with more than one configuration version you must also take care to replace <replaceable>VERSION</replaceable> with the name of the configuration version in use.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Examples</title>
			<example>
				<title>Getting a Configuration Value</title>
<screen>
# <command>ovirt-config</command> --get=SearchResultsLimit --cver=general
100
</screen>
			</example>
			<example>
				<title>Setting a Configuration Value</title>
<screen>
# <command>ovirt-config</command> --set SearchResultsLimit=50 --cver=general
</screen>
			</example>
	<!-- <xi:include href="http://topicrepo.englab.bne.redhat.com/TopicRepository/Tasks/oVirt/Setting_admin_internal_pwd.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	id="References_oVirt_3_Setting_admin_internal_pwd" -->
		</section>
<!-- A Reference provides additional information -->
<!-- A sample table layout is provided below -->
	


   <!-- Do not edit below this line! -->

   <!-- Injection Point: Related Overviews -->
   <!-- Injection Point: Related Concepts -->
   <!-- Injection Point: Related Tasks -->
</section>