<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE appendix PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM 'Installation_Guide.ent'>
<!ENTITY PRODUCT 'oVirt'>
<!ENTITY BOOKID 'Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization-Installation_Guide'>
<!ENTITY YEAR '2011'>
<!ENTITY HOLDER 'oVirt, Inc'>
]>
<appendix id="chap-Installation_Guide-Directory_Services">
	<title>Directory Services</title>
	<para>
		oVirt Engine is able to use both Active Directory and <acronym>IPA</acronym> Server for user authentication. This appendix documents the basic requirements for directory servers of either type to be added to the environment.
	</para>
	<para>
		Information on adding or removing directory services domains to the oVirt Engine configuration, once they have been created,  is available in <xref linkend="References_oVirt_3_Manage_Domains"/>.
	</para>	
	<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-Installing_the_Infrastructure-Directory_Services-IPA">
		<title>IPA Server</title>
		<para>
			<acronym>IPA</acronym> is an integrated security information management solution which combines Red Hat Enterprise Linux, oVirt Directory Server, <acronym>MIT</acronym> Kerberos, and <acronym>NTP</acronym>. It provides web browser and command-line interfaces, and its numerous administration tools allow an administrator to quickly install, set up, and administer one or more servers for centralized authentication and identity management. 
		</para>
		<para>
			The latest version of <acronym>IPA</acronym> extends the integration of <acronym>DNS</acronym>, includes a Certificate System Server, an enhanced administrative framework, support for host identities, netgroups, automount by location and other features. 
		</para>
		<formalpara>
			<title>Installation</title>
			<para>
				<acronym>IPA</acronym> focuses on making centralized identity and policy easy to manage in Linux and Unix environments, and includes compatibility with Windows environments. If you need assistance installing or configuring <acronym>IPA</acronym>, see the <citetitle>Red Hat Enterprise Linux — Enterprise Identity Management Guide</citetitle>.
			
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<xi:include href="./topics/Tasks/IPA/Adding_New_Users.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<!-- id="Tasks_IPA_Adding_New_Users" -->
	</section>
	<xi:include href="./topics/References/RHEV/2.3/Active_Directory.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
	<!-- id="References_oVirt_3_Active_Directory" -->
</appendix>