<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE preface PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Installation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<preface id="pref-Installation_Guide-Preface">
	<title>Preface</title>
	<para>
		The oVirt Project platform is a richly featured virtualization management solution providing fully integrated management across virtual machines. It is based on the leading open source virtualization platform and provides superior technical capabilities. The platform offers scalable management of large numbers of virtual machines.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-Preface-About_this_Guide">
		<title>About this Guide</title>
		<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-Preface-About_this_Guide-Audience">
			<title>Audience</title>
			<para>
				This guide is intended to provide detailed instruction on the installation and configuration of oVirt Project. A background in the administration of systems running oVirt Project Enterprise Linux is recommended. Experience with previous versions of oVirt Project, while beneficial, is not required.
			</para>
			<para>
				Customers with an Evaluation license should, in the first instance, consult the <citetitle>Evaluation Guide</citetitle> for a more streamlined installation experience. This guide will discuss all installation options in their entirety.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-Preface-About_this_Guide-Overview">
			<title>Overview</title>
			<para>
				Completion of the procedures outlined within this guide will result in a working oVirt Project environment. The environment produced will be configured to the level such that it can be used to create, run, and manage virtual machines. 
			</para>
		</section>
		<!--<xi:include href="Documentation_Suite.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"></xi:include>-->
	</section>
	<xi:include href="Common_Content/Conventions.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"></xi:include>
	<!-- NEED A REWRITTEN FEEDBACK SECTION FOR OVIRT, IRC CHANNELS, LISTS, ETC.
	<xi:include href="Feedback.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"><xi:fallback xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"><xi:include href="Common_Content/Feedback.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"></xi:include>
	</xi:fallback>
	</xi:include>
	-->
</preface>

