<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM 'Installation_Guide.ent'>
<!ENTITY PRODUCT 'oVirt'>
<!ENTITY BOOKID 'Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization-Installation_Guide'>
<!ENTITY YEAR '2011'>
<!ENTITY HOLDER 'oVirt, Inc'>
]>
<chapter id="chap-Installation_Guide-System_Requirements">
	<title>System Requirements</title>
	<para>
		This chapter outlines the hardware and software requirements for installing the oVirt platform. The requirements outlined herein are based on the minimum requirements for successful installation, configuration, and operation of a oVirt environment.
	</para>
	<para>
		Production oVirt installations will have additional requirements in line with the relative workloads expected of them. The additional requirements for your specific implementation of the oVirt product need to be determined by your solution architect. Guidance on planning your oVirt environment is provided in <xref linkend="chap-Installation_Guide-Planning_the_Data_Center"/>. 
	</para>
	<important>
		<title>Important — Listed Requirements are Mandatory</title>
		<para>
			All listed requirements must be met <emphasis>before</emphasis> installation commences. Without the listed requirements installation of a fully functional oVirt environment as described in this guide will <emphasis>not</emphasis> be possible.
		</para>
	</important>
	<para>
		Before commencing the installation you must consult the latest version of the oVirt Release Notes, available at <ulink url="http://www.ovirt.org/wiki/Release_Notes">http://www.ovirt.org/wiki/Release_Notes</ulink>.	
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-System_Requirements-Hardware_requirements">
		<title>Hardware requirements</title>
		<para>
			This section outlines the minimum hardware required to install, configure, and operate a oVirt environment. To setup a oVirt environment it is necessary to have, at least:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					one machine to act as the management server,
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					one or more machines to act as virtualization hosts - at least two are required to support migration and power management,
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					one or more machines to use as clients for accessing the Administration Portal.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					storage infrastructure provided by <acronym>NFS</acronym>, <acronym>iSCSI</acronym>, <acronym>SAN</acronym>, or local storage.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
			The hardware required for each of these systems is further outlined in the following sections. The oVirt environment also requires storage infrastructure that is accessible to the virtualization hosts. Storage infrastructure must be accessible using <acronym>NFS</acronym>, <acronym>iSCSI</acronym>, <acronym>FC</acronym>, or locally attached to virtualization hosts.
		</para>
		<xi:include href="./topics/References/RHEV/2.3/Manager_Requirements.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<!-- id="References_oVirt_3_Manager_Requirements" -->
		<xi:include href="./topics/References/RHEL/6/RHEVH/Support_Limits_List.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<!-- id="References_RHEL_6_oVirtH_Support_Limits_List" -->
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-System_Requirements-Software_requirements">
		<title>Software requirements</title>
		<!-- TODO: Downstream (RHEV) has a section on operating system requirements here, which lists the support RHEL versions. To be more distribution agnostic we need to provide a more generally applicable support statement here along the lines of you need a system with VDSM x.y.z, libvirt x.y.z, and qemu x.y.z - leaving users to try new and different things. If someone manages to get these dependencies and the boostrap working on something more exotic then all power to them!-->
		<important>
			<title>Important — Supported Locales</title>
			<para>
				The oVirt Engine setup script, <command>engine-setup</command>, supports the <literal>en_US.UTF-8</literal>, <literal>en_US.utf8</literal>, and <literal>en_US.utf-8</literal> locales. Attempts at installation on systems where the locale in use is not one of these supported values will fail. 
			</para>
		</important>
		<xi:include href="./topics/References/RHEV/2.3/Admin_Client_Requirements.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
		<!-- id="References_oVirt_3_Admin_Client_Requirements" -->		
		<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-Installing_the_Infrastructure-Directory_Services">
			<title>Directory Services</title>
			<para>
				The term directory service refers to the collection of software, hardware, and processes that store information about an enterprise, subscribers, or both, and make that information available to users. A directory service consists of at least one instance of Directory Server and at least one directory client program. Client programs can access names, phone numbers, addresses, and other data stored in the directory service.
			</para>
			<para>
				The oVirt platform provides its own internal <systemitem>admin</systemitem> user. Authentication for other users is supported by attaching directory services domains using the provided domain management tool, <command>ovirt-manage-domains</command>. Currently the two supported providers of directory services for use with the oVirt Engine are Identity, Policy, and Audit (<acronym>IPA</acronym>) and Microsoft Active Directory.
			</para>
			<para>
				For more information on configuring directory services see <xref linkend="chap-Installation_Guide-Directory_Services"/>. 
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="sect-Installation_Guide-Installing_the_Infrastructure-Firewall">
			<title>Firewall Configuration</title>
			<para>
				This section documents the firewall requirements of the oVirt environment. The ports that need to be opened, the type of traffic the port is used for, and the source of traffic which will be received on the port will be covered for the:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						oVirt Engine,
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						virtualization hosts, and
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						directory server.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>
				While specific configuration instructions for additional network infrastructure which may exist between these systems will not be covered it is intended that the information provided will assist with this task. 
			</para>
			<xi:include href="./topics/References/RHEV/2.3/Manager_Firewall_Requirements.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
			<!-- id="References_oVirt_3_Manager_Firewall_Requirements" -->
			<xi:include href="./topics/References/RHEV/2.3/Host_Firewall_Requirements.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
			<!-- id="References_oVirt_3_Host_Firewall_Requirements" -->
			<xi:include href="./topics/References/RHEV/2.3/Directory_Firewall_Requirements.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
			<!-- id="References_oVirt_3_Directory_Firewall_Requirements" -->
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
